（上条(かみじょう)）
御坂妹が死んだ
Misaka's sister died.
That was when one sister after another showed up all of a sudden.
…と思ったら
次から次へと 別の妹が現れた
How many sisters are there?
あいつら 一体 何人姉妹？
それは ともかく 妹達(シスターズ)？　実験？
But anyway, "Sisters"? Experiment?
Something out of this world
is happening in this Academy City.
この学園都市で 何か
とんでもないことが起こってる
What's going on, Shocker?
どういうことだ？　ビリビリ
お前は何か知ってるのか？
～♪
#12 Level Six
Absolute Power
"What is an esper ability" you ask?
（小萌(こもえ)）
“超能力とは何なのか”ですか？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん
（小萌）簡単に言っちゃえば―
To put it simply, it's just Schrödinger's Theory.
シュレディンガーの
理論なんですけど
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
シュレディンガー？
Schrödinger?
He was a quantum physicist...
量子力学の先生で
...and is famous for the "Schrödinger's cat" experiment.
“シュレディンガーの猫”という
お話を残しています
It was a very cruel experiment, so let me modify it a bit.
果てしなく残酷なので
ちょっとアレンジしますよ
I have a box in my hand.
ここに ひとつの箱があります
この中に何が入っているでしょう？
What's inside the box?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
う～ん…
そんなのチョコに決まってるんだよ
Chocolate, of course.
That's a box for chocolates.
だって それ チョコの箱だもん
You're wrong, unfortunately.
（小萌）
残念でした
アメ玉が入っているのです
Candy balls are inside.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）え～っ？　なに それ
（姫神(ひめがみ)）焼けた
That's cheap!
It's cooked.
はい シスターちゃん
この箱には何が入っているでしょう
Okay, Sister.
What's inside this box?
You just said there were candy balls inside.
アメ玉が入ってるって
自分で言ったじゃん
（小萌）
そうです　けど 先生が
ウソをついている可能性もあります
Yes, but there is also a possibility that I just lied.
50% it could be chocolate, 50% it could be candy balls.
（小萌）
チョコ 50パーセント
アメ玉 50パーセント
You won't know until you open the box.
開けてみないと分かりません
Here.
はい　どうぞ
A single ball of chocolate.
ちょこっとチョコが１コ　オチなし
No punchline.
Okay, Sister.
はい シスターちゃん
この箱には何が入っているでしょう
What's inside this box?
I saw there was a chocolate inside already.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
チョコ入ってるの見たもん
Indeed, because you just saw it,
most people would say that it's 100% chocolate.
確かに さっき見たことで
普通の人は―
チョコ100パーセントだと
思うでしょう
But what if there were people that thought there was a candy ball inside?
（小萌）
でも アメ玉が入ってると
思う人がいたら？
その可能性を信じて
それを手に入れたら？
What if they believed in that possibility and got a candy ball in the end?
For those people who can replace
normal reality with their own reality,
まともな現実から切り離され
自分だけの現実を手に入れた人を
we call them "espers".
私たちは“超能力者”と呼ぶのです
Why...
（美琴(みこと)）
どうして…
どうして
こんなことになっちゃったのかな
Why did it end up like this?
（美琴）
わあ…
Excuse me.
（医師Ａ）失礼
（美琴）うん？
Are you the famous Misaka Mikoto?
（医師Ａ）
君が あの御坂美琴君かい？
世の中には―
There are many handicapped people in pain who can't even move their own limbs.
自分の手足も自由に動かせずに
苦しんでいる人が大勢いるんだ
It won't stop raining.
Ame ga furiyamanai
雨は降り止まない
（医師Ｂ）
脳の命令というのは―
Commands from the brain are transmitted via signals to the muscles.
電気信号によって
筋肉に伝えられる
Isogi ashi wo hikitome
I stop my hurrying legs,
急ぎ足を引きとめ
If we had the power to control the electricity within our body,
もし生体電気を操る力があれば―
救いの光を与えることが
できるかもしれない
we might be able to provide those people with hope.
Aseridasu kokoro wo itazura ni jirashiteiru
Purposely teasing my anxious heart.
焦りだす心をいたずらにじらしている
（医師Ｃ）
あなたの能力を応用すれば
みんなを救えるかもしれないのよ
If we could apply your power, then we might be able to save a lot of people.
Hey, have you heard?
（生徒Ａ）
ねえ　知ってる？
学園都市のどこかで―
The rumor about military clones being produced somewhere inside this Academy City.
軍用クローンが
作られてるってウワサ
Tachidomaru koto sae wasurekaketa ano hi
On the day I nearly forgot even how to stop,
立ち止まる事さえ忘れかけたあの日
They're using a Level 5's DNA as a map, right?
（生徒Ｂ）
レベル５のＤＮＡマップを
使ってるって話でしょう？
Could it be that girl in our class?
（生徒Ｃ）
それって
もしかして ウチのクラスの？
Kizukasareta keshiki
The scenery that was shown to me...
気づかされた景色
Ridiculous.
ばかばかしい
Kanjite yo
Feel it
感じてよ
Kawasareru ashinami no oto kotoba wo nakushita hieta michi
The sound of footsteps overlapping, the cold road that lost its words.
交わされる足並みの音　言葉を無くした冷えた道
Sukoshi dake nagasareta toki modoshite hizashi matou yo
Turn back the time that flowed by a little and await the rays of the sun.
少しだけ流された時間戻して日差し待とうよ
Help...
助けて…
助けてよ
Help...
うん？　猫？
A cat?
（上条）
おい
Hey.
What are you doing?
（上条）
何やってんだ？　お前
フゥ…
フン…
どこで何をしようが勝手でしょう
I can do whatever I want, wherever I want.
I am Railgun, a Level 5.
私はレベル５の“超電磁砲(レールガン)”なのよ
Delinquents that approach me for some nightly pleasure don't count as danger.
夜遊びした程度で
寄ってくる不良なんて―
危険のうちに入らないわよ
To begin with, you don't have the right to lecture me.
そもそも あんたなんかに
言われる筋合いなんてないけど
やめろよ
Cut it out.
Cut what out?
やめろって何を？
A little walk at night and you're telling cute lil' Mikoto-chan who gave you some juice after kicking a vending machine-
自販機に蹴り入れて
ジュースもらってる美琴ちゃんに
今更 夜歩きくらいで そんな…
（上条）
“樹形図の設計者(ツリーダイアグラム)を用いて―”
"From the estimated calculation using Tree Diagram..."
“演算した結果”…
“128種類の戦場を用意し―”
"By preparing 128 different battlefields..."
"...and killing Railgun 128 times..."
“128回
超電磁砲(レールガン)を殺害することで―”
“アクセラレータは レベル６へ
進化することが判明した”
"...Accelerator will be able to evolve into a Level 6..."
“超電磁砲(レールガン)は
128人も用意できないため―”
"As it is impossible to prepare 128 Railguns,"
"we have set our eyes upon the Level 5 Mass Production Project, 'Sisters', progressing in parallel."
“同時期に進行していた
レベル５量産計画の妹達(シスターズ)に着目”
"Via this re-calculation, by preparing 20,000 different battlefields and killing 20,000 Sisters,"
“再演算の結果―”
“２万種類の戦場を用意し―”
“２万人の妹達(シスターズ)を
殺害することで―”
"the same results can be achieved."
“同じ結果が得られることが
分かった”
In other words, your sisters were created for
an experiment that would give birth to a Level 6...
つまりだ　お前の妹たちは―
レベル６を生みだす実験のために
作られ 殺されるってことだろう？
...and getting killed through the process, right?
あ～あ…
なんで こんなことしちゃうかな
Ahh, why are you doing this?
The fact you have those papers means you went into my room without my permission, right?
それ持ってるってことは―
あんた 私の部屋に 勝手に
上がり込んだってことでしょう
Usually, that would be a death sentence.
普通だったら死刑よ 死刑
結局 それを見て
あんたは 私が心配だと思ったの？
So, I take it you got worried about me after reading all those papers?
許せないって思ったの？
You thought that this was unforgivable?
心配したに決まってんだろう
Of course, I'm worried.
まあ ウソでも―
Well, I guess it's always better to have someone say that even if it's a lie.
そう言ってくれる人がいるだけ
マシってとこかしら
I'm not lying.
（上条）ウソじゃねえよ
（美琴）なに？
What?
I said, I'm not lying!
ウソじゃねえって言ってるだろう！
I'll apologize for going into your room without your permission.
（上条）
勝手に 部屋に上がったことは謝る
あとで いくらでも
電撃 浴びせりゃいいだろう
I'll take however many lightning attacks you'll shower me with later.
And, what are you doing?
…で お前は何をしてるんだ？
I don't believe you obtained this through proper channels either.
これも まともな手段で
手に入れた物とは思えない
この研究所の所についてる印は
何なんだ？
What are these marks around this research facility?
（美琴）
これじゃ まるで―
They look like "shot down" marks, don't they?
撃墜マークみたい …かしら？
You're probably thinking the right thing.
合ってるわよ それで
つっても バカ正直に―
It's not like I'm firing my railgun all over the place, you know?
超電磁砲(レールガン)ぶっ放したわけじゃ
ないけど
研究所の機材って
１台数億とかするでしょう
Machines in research facilities cost tens of millions each, right?
I eradicated them completely through the help of the net.
ネットを介して
そいつを私の力で根こそぎドカン
As a result, the research facilities have closed down,
その結果 研究所は閉鎖
プロジェクトは凍結
and the project was frozen... that was my plan...
…てなるはずだったんだけどね
Was?
（上条）
“はずだった”？
But no matter how many I destroy,
けど どれだけ つぶしても―
実験は すぐに
ほかの研究所に引き継がれる
some other research facility takes over right away.
To those scientists, Level 6, something they've never seen, must be a pretty enticing concept.
学者さんには
前人未踏のレベル６ってのが―
よっぽど おいしく見えるのね
Those girls... refer to themselves as experimental animals...
あの子たちね 自分たちのことを
“実験動物”っていうのよ
...and they know the context of what they say...
（美琴）
それが どういうことなのか
正しく理解しててね
人間のクローンって
国際法違反なんだろう？
Human clones are a violation of international law, aren't they?
発覚させちまえば 理事会だって…
If you can expose that, even the Board would...
This city is under surveillance by the Tree Diagram satellite.
（美琴）
この街は―
樹形図の設計者(ツリーダイアグラム)って衛星で
監視されてるのよ
理事会だって
黙認してるってことでしょう
It must mean the Board has given it a tacit consent.
This was a problem I started.
これは 私の引き起こした問題なの
That's why I need to be the one that saves them.
だから あの子たちは
私の手で助け出すべきなのよ
It's actually quite simple if you think about it...
考えてみれば 簡単なのよね
This experiment is one that seeks to make Accelerator stronger.
この実験は アクセラレータを
強くするためのもの
If the centerpiece of this experiment, Accelerator, is gone,
アクセラレータって柱がなくなれば
実験は空中分解してしまう
then the experiment will dissolve into thin air by itself.
You're lying.
（上条）ウソだな
（美琴）えっ？
You can't defeat Accelerator.
お前にアクセラレータは倒せない
You would've done that first if you could've.
そんなことができるのなら
お前は 真っ先にやってるはずだ
Which means, you couldn't even if you wanted to.
…てことは やりたくても
できないってことだろう
You weren't a match for Accelerator to begin with.
お前とアクセラレータじゃ
はなから勝負にならないとかな
Why didn't you ask for my help?
なんで相談しなかったんだ？
If you know you can't take care of this by yourself,
１人で解決できないって
分かったら―
couldn't you just ask someone for help?
ほかの誰かに助けを
求めりゃいいだけの話じゃねえか
（美琴）
２万人の妹達(シスターズ)を用意したのはなぜ？
Why did you think there were 20,000 sisters prepared?
Because they couldn't prepare 128 Railguns.
超電磁砲(レールガン)を
128人も用意できないから
Why did they need 128 Railguns?
超電磁砲(レールガン)を
128人も必要とするのは なぜ？
Because by killing Railgun 128 times, Accelerator can evolve into a Level 6.
（美琴）
超電磁砲(レールガン)を128回 殺せば―
アクセラレータが
レベル６に進化するから
Suppose I'm not even worth that much.
もしも私に
それだけの価値がなかったら？
Suppose even after killing me 128 times,
he doesn't reach Level 6,
128回 殺しても
レベル６なんか たどりつけない
and that I'm able to let those scientists know their failure...
研究者たちに
そう思わせることができたら？
実際 樹形図の設計者(ツリーダイアグラム)は
私とアクセラレータが戦えば―
In fact, Tree Diagram has calculated that I would die by the 125th move of our battle.
185手で 私が死ぬっていう
計算結果をはじき出してる
フフッ… けど もし 最初の１手で
私が ぶざまに敗北したとしたら？
So what if I lost miserably in the first move?
その結果を見た研究者たちは
きっと こう思うわ
After seeing those results,
those scientists would definitely think...
...that "things machines do are indeed wrong"...
“やっぱり 機械のやることには
間違いがあるんだ”ってね
たとえ１回 ごまかせたとしたって
Even if you could get by them for one calculation,
they'd just resimulate and restart the experiment again.
演算し直したら
実験は再開されちまうだろう
それはないわよ
That won't happen.
樹形図の設計者(ツリーダイアグラム)はね
Tree Diagram was destroyed by an attack from Earth's surface a few weeks ago.
実は 数週間前に
地上からの攻撃で撃墜されてるの
原因は不明らしいけど
The reason seems unknown, but...
That means, they won't be able to resimulate.
だから 再計算は もうできない
However much data they still have,
データが いくら残ってたって
分析することができなきゃ―
if they can't analyze it, they still have no choice but to stop the experiment.
実験全体を
ストップさせるしかないわ
（上条）
そっか　お前…
I see.
You want to die, huh?
死のうとしてるんだな？
Yes.
（上条）
お前が死ぬことで―
With your death, the remaining
10,000 sisters of yours will be saved?
残る１万人の妹たちが
救われるって 本気で
You seriously think that?
そうよ
Yup.
I'm going to Accelerator's location now.
私は これから
アクセラレータの所に行く
私が割り込んで
実験そのものを終わらせてやるわ
I'm going to stick my neck right into this and stop the experiment in its tracks.
どいて
Out of the way.
No.
（上条）どかねえよ
（美琴）はぁ？
Do you understand what you're saying?
あんた
自分が何言ってるか分かってる？
If I don't die, then 10,000 sisters will be killed!
私が死ななきゃ
１万人の妹達(シスターズ)が殺されんのよ
Don't tell me you're thinking it's okay for them to die because they're clones?!
まさか クローンだから
死んでもかまわないって―
思ってるじゃないでしょうね？
（上条）
あいつらが
死んでもいい存在だなんて思わねえ
I don't think it's okay for them to die.
だからって 何かほかに
方法があるってわけでもない
But that doesn't mean I have
some solution for them to not die.
Even so, I can't step aside.
それでもイヤなんだ
そう　あんたは私を止めるのね
I see...
You're gonna stop me, eh?
You don't care about the lives of my 10,000 sisters, huh?
１万人の妹達(シスターズ)の命なんて
どうでもいいっていうのね
I can't bear the sight of them getting hurt.
私は あの子たちが傷つくのは
見てられないの
That's why I'll save them with my own hands.
（美琴）
だから この手で救ってみせる
This is my final warning!
これが最後の通告よ
そこをどきなさい！
Move aside!
I still don't know what kind of power you have,
あんたが どんな力を持ってるか
いまだに分からないけど
but I'm not allowed to lose today!
今日は負けるわけにはいかない
だから
あんたも死ぬ気で拳を握りなさい
So put up your dukes with death in mind!
If not, you will  die!
（美琴）
じゃないと…
ホントに死ぬわよ！
Hey!
ちょっと！
何やってんのよ？　あんた
What do you think you're doing?!
力ずくで私を止めるっていうの？
Are you trying to stop me by force?
Fine.
いいわよ
それなら こっちも遠慮しない
Then I've got nothing to hold back either.
たとえ あんたが無抵抗でも
私は あんたを撃ち抜く！
Even if you're defenseless, I will shoot through you.
（上条）戦わない
（美琴）えっ？
I will not fight you.
I will not... fight you...
（上条）戦わない
（美琴）はぁ？
（美琴）
バカじゃないの？
Are you stupid or something?
There's no path open to me besides this one.
私には
もう この方法以外には道はないの
これは あんたの知ってる
日常なんかじゃない
This is not the daily life you know.
This is hell where 10,000 people are killed without a second thought!
（美琴）
１万人以上の人間が 簡単に
殺されてる非日常の地獄なのよ
Do you think that "I will not fight" will work?
（美琴）
戦わないだなんて―
そんな日和(ひよ)った意見が
通るはずないじゃない
それでも…
Even so... Even so, I don't wish to fight you.
それでも 戦いたくない
戦えって言ってるのに…
I'm telling you to fight me...
戦えって言ってんのよ！
I'm telling you... to fight me!
次は本気で ぶち抜くわよ
I will drill a hole in you for real next time.
戦う気があるなら 拳を握れ
戦う気がないなら 立ち塞がるな！
Put up your dukes if you're going to fight me!
Move out of the way if you're not going to!
Don't try to stop someone's will with your half-assed feelings!!
半端な気持ちで 人の願いを
踏みにじってんじゃないわよ！
ハアッ！
（放出音）
（スパーク音）
そんな…
How come...
W-Why...
な… なんで？
（美琴）
なんで戦わないの？
Why... won't you fight me?
（上条）知らねえよ…
（美琴）えっ？
Beats... me...
I don't know... why I won't fight you...
戦いたくない理由なんて
分からねえよ
ほかに何かいい案があるかどうかも
分かんねえ
I don't know... whether there are other good solutions either...
But... I don't like it...
（上条）
けど イヤなんだよ
お前が傷つくところなんて
見たくねえんだよ
I don't want to see you get hurt.
なんで
お前が死ななきゃいけないんだよ？
Why... do you have to die?
Why does someone have to get killed?
どうして 誰かが
殺されなくちゃならないんだよ？
（上条）
そんなの納得できるはずねえだろう
There's no way I'd accept something like that!
Help...
（美琴）
助けて…
助けてよ
Help...
（美琴）うるさいのよ
（上条）えっ…
Shut up...
私には 今更―
I don't deserve those words anymore.
そんな言葉をかけてもらえるような
資格はないんだから
Even if there is a world that everyone wants,
where everyone is smiling...
（美琴）
仮に 誰もが笑って 誰もが望む―
そんな幸せな世界があったとして
そこに私の居場所はないんだから
...I don't have a place in that world!
（上条）
お前だって気づいてんだろう
You already realize...
こんな方法じゃ
誰も救われないってことくらい
...that your way won't save anyone...
Even if you die and save your 10,000 sisters' lives...
たとえ お前が死んで―
１万人の妹達(シスターズ)の命が
助けられたとしたって
そんな方法で助けられて―
You think they would thank you for the way you did it?
あいつらが感謝するとでも
思ってんのか？
Shut up...
うるさい　もう黙って戦いなさいよ
Just shut up and fight me.
私は あんたが思ってるような
善人じゃない！
I'm not the kind of good person you think I am!
ハァ…
私は もう
１万人以上の人間を殺したのよ
I've killed more than 10,000 people.
そんな悪党が この世界で
生きてていい理由なんか 何もない
There is no reason for a villain like me to be living in this world... none!
一体 どうして―
Why in the world... are you standing up for a villain like me?
あんたは こんな悪党のために
立ち上がってんのよ？
（上条）悪党なんかじゃねえ
（美琴）ハッ…
You're not a villain.
だったら
なんで俺は生きてるんだよ？
Then why am I alive?
With that much electric flow,
there's no way a normal human can live.
あんだけの電流 浴びて―
普通の人間が
生きてられるわけねえだろう
無意識に
手加減してたんじゃねえのか？
You went easy without knowing it, didn't you?
（美琴）
手加減？　そんなはずない
Went easy?
No way.
私は あんたを殺す気だった
I wanted you dead...
あんたが抵抗してこないって
知ってて それでも…
...even knowing... you wouldn't resist...
And yet you didn't kill me!
それでも 俺は殺せなかった
お前にとって―
For you, to use your own life to save
your sisters might've been your last dream.
自分の命で 妹たちを助けることは
最後の夢だったのかもしれないけど
結局は その夢を
奪おうとした男さえ殺せないほど
But you're too good of a person to kill the guy who's trying to take away that last dream of yours, aren't you?
善人だったってだけじゃねえか
あの子たちを助けるには
もう私が死ぬしかないんだから
The only way to save them is for me to die!
Then let that be, no?
だから それでいいじゃない！
If everyone can be saved with my death...
私１人が死んで
それで みんなが救われるなら―
Isn't that a wonderful thing?!
それは
とても すばらしいことでしょう？
If you think so, then move out of the way!!!
そう思うなら そこをどいてよ！
I will not.
（上条）どかない
（美琴）ハッ…
（美琴）
死ぬわよ
You're gonna die.
Eat this one head on, and you won't be able to live for sure.
今度の一撃をまともに食らったら
あんたは絶対に生きられない
So...
だから
死にたくなければ どきなさい！
...move out of the way if you don't want to die!!!
I will not.
（上条）どかない
（美琴）ハッ…
やめて…
Stop...
Stop... already...
もう やめて…
もう やめてよ
Stop already...
（上条）
あいつは“死ぬしかない”と言った
～♪
She said she had no choice but to die.
“死にたい”でも
“死ねばいい”でもなく
Neither does she want to die, nor should she.
“死ぬしかない”だ
She had no choice but to die.
何か ほかに選択肢はないのか
Isn't there any other choice?
考えよう　新たな…
Think.
A new... A new option...
新たな選択肢を
To those scientists, Level 6, something they've never seen, must be a pretty enticing concept.
（美琴）
お偉い学者さんには―
前人未踏のレベル６ってのが
よっぽど おいしく見えるのね
実験を止めるには…
To stop the experiment, I must let them realize that nothing good will come out of the experiment.
そもそも 実験が―
何の利益も生みださないものだと
思い込ませなければならない
Huh...
あれ？
Next Episode
（上条）
ほんの僅かな奇跡を求めて
御坂妹は実験場へと向かう
Looking for a very faint miracle to happen,
Misaka's sister moves toward the experiment location.
そこで待つ学園都市最強のレベル５
その力とは
Awaiting her there is the Academy City's strongest Level 5.
What are his powers?
Next time, "Accelerator".
次回 「一方通行(アクセラレータ)」
When science and magic cross paths,
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
this epic will begin!